<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Monitoring on Ding&#39;s Coding Forge</title>
    <link>https://dingyu.dev/tags/monitoring/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Monitoring on Ding&#39;s Coding Forge</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ding&#39;s Coding Forge</title>
      <url>https://dingyu.dev/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://dingyu.dev/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.144.0</generator>
    <language>ko</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://dingyu.dev/tags/monitoring/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>[EDA] Kafka (MSK) Monitoring with Burrow Prometheus And Thanos</title>
      <link>https://dingyu.dev/posts/dance-with-burrow/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dingyu.dev/posts/dance-with-burrow/</guid>
      <description>People often rely solely on basic Kafka metrics like Input/Output Bytes, missing crucial insights into their event-driven architecture. This post demonstrates how to set up comprehensive topic-level monitoring for Kafka (AWS MSK) using Burrow, Prometheus, and Thanos. By combining Burrow for accurate consumer lag tracking, Prometheus for metric collection, and Thanos for long-term data storage and high availability, you&amp;#39;ll achieve effective Kafka monitoring without the high costs and limitations of cloud-native solutions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[LGTM] Elasticsearch to Loki 전환기</title>
      <link>https://dingyu.dev/posts/es-to-loki/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dingyu.dev/posts/es-to-loki/</guid>
      <description>This article explores the transition from Elasticsearch to Loki for cost-efficient log management, highlighting key differences in storage, indexing, and query performance. It covers best practices for optimizing Loki&amp;#39;s labeling strategy, managing chunk storage, and handling high-cardinality data. Additionally, it provides a step-by-step guide to configuring Grafana dashboards for efficient log analysis, including Raw Logs, Error Logs, TPS (P50/P99), Log Distributions, and Table Views.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
